<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configure on Gary Flynn</title>
    <link>https://garyflynn.com/tags/configure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configure on Gary Flynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 15:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.com/tags/configure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.5&#43; - Increase Session Timeout</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session will timeout after 30 minutes of inactivity. For those looking to increase the session timeout value, this hasn&#39;t been possible before vRealize Automation 8.5. This all changes with the release of vRealize Automation 8.5, as documented in the release notes here.
To increase the session timeout from the default 30 minutes, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Hide Quickstart UI</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-hide-quickstart-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-hide-quickstart-ui/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session log you into the Services page, when you and your users are greeted with the Quickstart banner. The easiest way to remove this is to configure a vSphere Cloud Account, however for some environments, vSphere isn&#39;t an endpoint used. In this case, to remove the banner, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager Part 2 - Deploying an Application</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-2-deploying-an-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-2-deploying-an-application/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Part one of this blog covered the installation and configuration of vRSLCM which can be found here and this post will cover deploying your first application.
Create an Environment In vRSLCM, the concept of environments can mean two different things. It could mean Dev/Test/Prod where multiple applications are deployed in one environment or it could mean Dev vRA/Dev vROps/Test vRA/Test vROps where each environment and application combination has its own environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start the vRealize Orchestrator Configurator Service</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/start-the-vrealize-orchestrator-configurator-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 15:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/start-the-vrealize-orchestrator-configurator-service/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Once vRealize Automation 7.x is deployed, you must manually start the vRealize Orchestrator Configurator service to access the Configuration interface.
To do this, log into the vRealize Automation appliance by SSH using PuTTY (or your preferred Secure Shell client).
    Run this command to verify that the service is set to automatically start.
1chkconfig vco-configurator If the service reports &amp;quot;off&amp;quot;, run this command to enable an automatic restart of the vRealize Orchestrator Configurator service when the vRealize Automation appliance is rebooted in future.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager Part 1 - Install &amp; Configure</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-1-install-configure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-1-install-configure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the least discussed products from VMware, vRealize Lifecycle Manager (vRLCM), really is a fantastic product! I have been deploying vRealize Automation (vRA) since it was first purchased from DynamicOps and the first release of vCloud Automation Center was released. The vRealize suite of products have always been difficult to install and this product takes the majority of hassle out of this. This blog will cover the deployment of vRealize Lifecycle Manager.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi Install and Configure</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/esxi-install-and-configure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 09:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/esxi-install-and-configure/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide will cover the ESXi installation and configuration process. If installing ESXi onto a bare-metal server from a USB, follow my guide here on how to create a bootable USB installer. Once you have your installation media ready, either a USB installer or the downloaded ISO, insert / attach the media and power on your server. If you are doing this in a nested ESXi environment, attach the media via the VMware Remote Console.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
