<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vRealize on Gary Flynn</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/vrealize/</link><description>Recent content in vRealize on Gary Flynn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/vrealize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMworld 2021 vRealize Announcements</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vmworld-2021-vrealize-announcements/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vmworld-2021-vrealize-announcements/</guid><description>
VMworld 2021 was still being held online only this year, which meant there was no shortage of announcements and information available for anyone interested. With a few large announcements including the Project Ensemble Tech Preview and Skyline Advisor Pro, there is plenty to keep an eye on in this space. Below I've listed a few things for each of the vRealize Suite products which caught my attention. Leave a comment below on what you're looking forward to in this next release!</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ - Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout-comments/</guid><description>
John Dias - Nov 3, 2021
Gary, this doesn't seem to impact embedded vRO - do you know a trick for that?
#### [Gary]( "garyflynnis@gmail.com") - Nov 4, 2021 G'day John. Unfortunately not. I mention this in the article, but for whatever reason, I can't see this change affecting vRO. I'm hoping it's a bug, but suspect it might be a 'feature'. All the best. Gary</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ – Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</guid><description>
By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session will timeout after 30 minutes of inactivity. For those looking to increase the session timeout value, this hasn't been possible before vRealize Automation 8.5. This all changes with the release of vRealize Automation 8.5, as documented in the release notes here.
To increase the session timeout from the default 30 minutes, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL.</description></item><item><title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform-comments/</guid><description>
vRA &amp;amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy – Gary Flynn - May 2, 2021
[…] Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform […]</description></item><item><title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</guid><description>
VMware has created a HashiCorp Terraform provider which can be used to set up your vRealize Automation (vRA) infrastructure, along with requesting deployments and consuming XaaS resources. This post will cover the basics of setting up vRA using Terraform.
The first two posts in this series cover the basics of Infrastructure as Code with vRA and Terraform along with creating your first Terraform configuration to deploy a vSphere virtual machine. To get started, have a read of the documentation available for either vRA 8 or vRA 7.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range-comments/</guid><description>
Josh - May 3, 2021
We had attempted this in our environment unsuccessfully. After opening a case with vmware, we were informed that these steps are incorrect, and were provided the following procedure: • execute 'vracli upgrade exec -y --prepare --profile k8s-subnets' • take VM snapshot • change the subnets on the same node the upgrade command was started: 'vracli network k8s-subnets --cluster-cidr 10.224.0.0/22 --service-cidr 10.224.4.0/22' • execute upgrade with profile: 'vracli upgrade exec'</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for changing the IP address range used by the internal Kubernetes cluster, which is great news as many organisation already use the 10.244.0.0/21 address space. Unfortunately if your network already uses the ranges 10.244.0.0/22 or 10.244.4.0/22, you will likely encounter issues, such a provisioning timeouts.
To resolve this issue in vRA 8.2, run the below commands to view your current configuration, and to update to a new range.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed-comments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed-comments/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range – Gary Flynn - Dec 4, 2020
[…] when the Kubernetes internal IP address space is changed to use the 192.168.0.0/16 address space. This post resolves the issue, while VMware develop a patch to resolve the […]</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0 introduced a completely new architecture by running the vRA application itself on top of a Kubernetes (k8s) cluster. Unfortunately this was released with a hardcoded IP address range used by the internal k8s cluster. If your corporate network happened to be using the same IP addresses that were selected by the k8s cluster, then you would likely see plenty of errors in vRA.
Thankfully, vRealize Automation 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.2 - Terraform Configurations</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations-comments/</guid><description>
Using vRA 8.2 Terraform cloud templates to deploy AWS resources - TG-TEST100 - Jan 4, 2021
[…] vRealize Automation 8.2 – Terraform Configurations […]</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.2 - Terraform Configurations</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for running your Terraform (TF) configurations directly from the vRA interface. Simply register your code repository endpoint, either GitLab or GitHub, and select which Terraform configuration to run. The vRA logic will even map the deployed resources to your vRA Cloud Accounts, Cloud Zones, and deployed resource objects. This functionality is fantastic to extend the capabilities beyond the supported resource types. You could use the TF configurations to deploy an F5 load balancer, an Azure and AWS VM, as well as creating your Grafana dashboards and registering your Datadog agents all from a single configuration.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account-comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account-comments/</guid><description>
yuki - Apr 4, 2021
Thank you very much. Cloud Zone is created. But after 10 min i got error like this :com.amazonaws.services.s3.model.AmazonS3Exception: Service Unavailable (Service: Amazon S3; Status Code: 503; Error Code: 503 Service Unavailable; Request ID: null; S3 Extended Request ID: null; Proxy: proxy-service.prelude.svc.cluster.local) java.util.concurrent.CompletionException: com.amazonaws.services.ec2.model.AmazonEC2Exception: null (Service: AmazonEC2; Status Code: 503; Error Code: 503 Service Unavailable; Request ID: null; Proxy: proxy-service.prelude.svc.cluster.local) Do you know somting about this?</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Amazon Web Services (AWS) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For AWS, we simply need to head over to the AWS Console console.aws.amazon.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the AWS account you want to integrate with.
To integrate vRA 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager Part 2 - Deploying an Application</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-2-deploying-an-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-2-deploying-an-application/</guid><description>
Part one of this blog covered the installation and configuration of vRSLCM which can be found here and this post will cover deploying your first application.
Create an Environment In vRSLCM, the concept of environments can mean two different things. It could mean Dev/Test/Prod where multiple applications are deployed in one environment or it could mean Dev vRA/Dev vROps/Test vRA/Test vROps where each environment and application combination has its own environment.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup GitHub Integration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration-comments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration-comments/</guid><description>
Nithin - Jul 4, 2021
Getting time out error and 404 error when synced with github for cloud templates and abx actions. How to resolve the issue ?</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup GitHub Integration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.x provides native integration to GitHub.com to share and sync your Blueprints and Action Based Extensibility (ABX) scripts. This integration is provided as a way to edit your blueprints and ABX scripts as Infrastructure as Code (IaC) objects and for vRA to then consume the changes once they are updated and committed to your repository. This integration is not designed as a way to backup or export your content to GitHub.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator - Kerberos Configuration File</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-orchestrator-kerberos-configuration-file-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 11:02:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-orchestrator-kerberos-configuration-file-comments/</guid><description>
SLiM - Dec 2, 2020
I think you may have a type-o for [domain_realm] Also please reference the VMware documentation for this * Configure Kerberos Authentication https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Orchestrator/8.2/com.vmware.vrealize.orchestrator-use-plugins.doc/GUID-1A829CCF-A147-422E-80B3-0819F8D6E6AE.html?hWord=N4IghgNiBcINYCcBGBWAdAYwPYDsBmIAvkA
#### [Gary]( "garyflynnis@gmail.com") - Dec 5, 2020 Hi Scott, Thanks for spotting the typo. All fixed now. I have also added a link to the document you mentioned. It looks like this documentation was only published in September of this year. Cheers, Gary</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator - Kerberos Configuration File</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-orchestrator-kerberos-configuration-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 11:02:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-orchestrator-kerberos-configuration-file/</guid><description>
To configure Kerberos authentication with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO), the krb5.conf file must be set up for your specific environment and the domain you are connecting to. The location of the krb5.conf file is different for different versions and deployments of vRO, so the below list shows the locations of the krb5.conf file for vRO 7 vs vRO 8 and standalone deployments vs embedded with vRA deployments.
In vRO 7.x standalone, the krb5.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Google Cloud Platform Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Google Cloud Platform (GCP) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For GCP, there is some preparation we need to do on the GCP Console, so head over to console.cloud.google.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Project you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Azure Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Microsoft Azure environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For Azure, there is some preparation we need to do on the Azure Portal, so head over to portal.azure.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Subscription you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup vSphere Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your vSphere environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For vSphere, enter the vCenter FQDN / IP address, the credentials to authenticate with and select a logical name. Under capabilities, enter &amp;quot;cloud:vsphere&amp;quot; as this will enable us to use tagging in the blueprint request forms.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020-comments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020-comments/</guid><description>
vSphere 7.0 Link-O-Rama » Welcome to vSphere-land! - Mar 2, 2020
[…] vRealize Suite Announcement – March 2020 (Gary Flynn) vRealize Management 8.1 (vROPS, vRLI, vRA): What’s new (JohannStander) vRealize Operations Manager (vROps) 8.1 – A True Multi-Cloud Management Platform (VirtualG) vRealize Automation 8.1 – Network Automation (vRA4U) vRealize Automation 8.1 – General Enhancements (Part 1) (vRA4U) vRealize Automation 8.1 – General Enhancements (Part 2) (vRA4U) […]
#### [Анонс VMware vSphere 7 | vMind.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</guid><description>
Today is a significant day for VMware with the announcements coming out primarily around vSphere 7 and the implementation of Project Tanzu. The vSphere client will now natively support running containers and VMs within the same unified console, the vSphere Client. One very interesting new feature is the VMware Lifecycle Manager (vLCM) that will be introduced to simplify the management of firmware, drivers and ESXi bundles. For more information on today's announcements, check out the blog here.</description></item><item><title>vRA 7.x vs vRA 8.x - Which Version to Deploy?</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/which-version-of-vra-to-deploy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 16:43:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/which-version-of-vra-to-deploy/</guid><description>
VMware has recently released vRealize Automation 8.0 and with this comes a complete redesign of the vRealize Automation product. Are you just starting out on your Cloud Management Platform (CMP) journey and not quite sure which version to deploy? Hopefully this blog will help you understand some of the key differences between vRA 7.x and vRA 8.x and some familiar features which are missing from vRA 8.x.
The first place to start is by reading this excellent blog post by Chip Zoller (daphnissov) on the VMware Community Forums.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Troubleshooting</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting-comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting-comments/</guid><description>
vSphere25 - Dec 4, 2019
Hi Gary, i have deployed VRA 8 and also synchronize Active directory, but i unable to access VRA using AD account, i have tested both admins and member accounts.
#### [Gary]( "garyflynnis@gmail.com") - Jan 1, 2020 Hey vSphere25, A couple things to check. - In vIDM 8, have you sync'ed your user ID / group so that is it visible in vIDM? - If the user is visible in vIDM, is the user visible in vRA 8 under the &amp;quot;Identity &amp;amp; Access Management&amp;quot; tab?</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Troubleshooting</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/</guid><description>
With the introduction of vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0, the traditional appliance VAMI page is gone. This is replaced with the vRA CLI and the kubernetes command line tools. This post will show some of the more common CLI commands you may need. To use all of the commands below, use SSH to connect to the appliance and log in with the root username and password.
Check Pods / 'Services' Status Display vRA Cluster Status Verify the vRA Deployment Status Check Deployment Log File Generate a Log Bundle Stopping / Shut down vRA Cluster Starting vRA Cluster vRA 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Services</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:47:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services-comments/</guid><description>
vRA &amp;amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy – Gary Flynn - Jan 5, 2021
[…] vRealize Automation Cloud is comprised of three services: Cloud Assembly, Service Broker and Code Stream. To understand these services more, have a read of this post. […]</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Services</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:47:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services/</guid><description>
In the previous post we configured vRA 8.0 with a vSphere endpoint and in this post we are going to cover the different Services which are available. vRA 8.0 has four main components or services, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Great, but what is the role of each service?
Image not found a.warning-link { color: inherit !important; font-weight: inherit !important; text-decoration: underline !important; border-bottom: none !</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Getting Started (Quickstart)</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:41:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</guid><description>
In the previous post we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRA and configure it for use. vRA 8.0 is a fundamental change from 7.x and it now consists of four main components, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Let's get vRA 8.0 configured! Load up the vRA homepage https:/// where you are greeted with the welcome page. One thing to note is that the new vRA 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Log Insight 8.x - Getting Started</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-log-insight-8x-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 10:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-log-insight-8x-getting-started/</guid><description>
In the previous post we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRLI and configure it for use. vRLI 8.0 has some significant improvements including Unlimited Exports of data (increased from 20,000 events), Content Pack Updates and a new OS in the form of Photon OS. For more information check out the VMware blog post here which includes details of how the single upgrade file will also move the OS from SUSE to Photon!</description></item><item><title>Downgrade / Remove vRA License</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/downgrade-remove-vra-license/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:09:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/downgrade-remove-vra-license/</guid><description>
I recently had the requirement to remove an existing vRealize Suite Enterprise key from vRealize Automation 7.3.1 and replace it with a vRealize Suite Advanced key. When you try to replace the license key from the VAMI, you will receive an error stating that you cannot downgrade license keys &amp;quot;Unable to downgrade existing license edition&amp;quot;. To replace the license you must do the following. Note, this is 100% not supported by VMware so use it at your own risk and always do it first in a test environment, and always ensure you have backups.</description></item><item><title>vRA / vRO - Add an Azure connection</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-vro-add-an-azure-connection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 13:20:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-vro-add-an-azure-connection/</guid><description>
Integrating vRA / vRO and Azure is available out-of-the-box with vRA 7.2+ and has been well documented by others for how to set the integration up (vaficionado.com).
The integration is fairly straightforward however I faced two main issues, the first being proxy settings and the second being an issue with the vRO workflow &amp;quot;Add an Azure connection&amp;quot;.
Update Azure Plugin To resolve other vRO / Azure bugs, ensure you update the Azure plugin in vRO to the latest version from https://kb.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager Part 1 - Install &amp; Configure</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-1-install-configure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-1-install-configure/</guid><description>
One of the least discussed products from VMware, vRealize Lifecycle Manager (vRLCM), really is a fantastic product! I have been deploying vRealize Automation (vRA) since it was first purchased from DynamicOps and the first release of vCloud Automation Center was released. The vRealize suite of products have always been difficult to install and this product takes the majority of hassle out of this. This blog will cover the deployment of vRealize Lifecycle Manager.</description></item></channel></rss>