<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Gary Flynn</title>
    <link>https://garyflynn.com/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Gary Flynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.com/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for changing the IP address range used by the internal Kubernetes cluster, which is great news as many organisation already use the 10.244.0.0/21 address space. Unfortunately if your network already uses the ranges 10.244.0.0/22 or 10.244.4.0/22, you will likely encounter issues, such a provisioning timeouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue in vRA 8.2, run the below commands to view your current configuration, and to update to a new range.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0 introduced a completely new architecture by running the vRA application itself on top of a Kubernetes (k8s) cluster. Unfortunately this was released with a hardcoded IP address range used by the internal k8s cluster. If your corporate network happened to be using the same IP addresses that were selected by the k8s cluster, then you would likely see plenty of errors in vRA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, vRealize Automation 8.2 added support for changing the internal IP address range used by the Kubernetes cluster. Unfortunately, there is a bug in the code where only the 10.0.0.0/8 and 127.0.0.0/8 address spaces are supported. If you choose to use the 192.168.0.0/16 address space, the vRA deployment won&#39;t start-up. When running the command &amp;quot;kubectl get pods -n prelude&amp;quot;, the &amp;quot;catalog-service-app&amp;quot; pod will show as 0/1 Ready, and Running.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
