<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vRSLCM on Gary Flynn</title>
    <link>https://garyflynn.com/tags/vrslcm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vRSLCM on Gary Flynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.com/tags/vrslcm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2021 vRealize Announcements</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vmworld-2021-vrealize-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vmworld-2021-vrealize-announcements/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VMworld 2021 was still held online only this year, which meant there was no shortage of announcements and information available for anyone interested. With a few large announcements including the Project Ensemble Tech Preview and Skyline Advisor Pro, there is plenty to keep an eye on in this space. Below I&#39;ve listed a few things for each of the vRealize Suite products which caught my attention. Leave a comment below on what you&#39;re looking forward to in this next release!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager Part 2 - Deploying an Application</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-2-deploying-an-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-part-2-deploying-an-application/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Part one of this blog covered the installation and configuration of vRSLCM which can be found here and this post will cover deploying your first application.
Create an Environment In vRSLCM, the concept of environments can mean two different things. It could mean Dev/Test/Prod where multiple applications are deployed in one environment or it could mean Dev vRA/Dev vROps/Test vRA/Test vROps where each environment and application combination has its own environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today is a significant day for VMware with the announcements coming out primarily around vSphere 7 and the implementation of Project Tanzu. The vSphere client will now natively support running containers and VMs within the same unified console, the vSphere Client. One very interesting new feature is the VMware Lifecycle Manager (vLCM) that will be introduced to simplify the management of firmware, drivers and ESXi bundles. For more information on today&#39;s announcements, check out the blog here.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite 2019 - Deploy using vRSLCM</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 09:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous post we went over the vRSLCM configuration and now we are ready to deploy the vRealize Suite of products. Before we start, I can not stress this enough... Read the release notes!! There are countless changes to each of the products and vRA 8.0 especially is missing some features which may return in vRA 8.1 or later.
 vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 - Release Notes vRealize Automation 8.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 Configuration</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 21:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the previous post we went over the vRSLCM Easy Installer which deployed vRSLCM 8.0 and vIDM 8.0. The installations went smoothly with no reported issues.
Let&#39;s log into the vRSLCM UI by navigating to https://&amp;lt;vRSLCM FQDN or IP&amp;gt;/ and log in with the username &amp;quot;admin@local&amp;quot; and the password you set in the deployment in the previous steps. Note the default username has changed from previous versions and is no longer admin@localhost.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite 2019 - Easy Installer</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VMware has just announced the latest release of the vRealize Suite (2019) and with it comes vRealize Automation 8.0 (vRA), vRealize Log Insight 8.0 (vRLI), vRealize Operations Manager 8.0 (vROps) and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 (vRSLCM). Noticeably absent is vRealize Business for Cloud (vRBC), as this product has been deprecated and the functionality has been migrated to vROps.
 Announcing General Availability of vRealize Suite 2019, vCloud Suite 2019, and vCloud Suite 2019 Platinum!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
