<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>8.x on Gary Flynn</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/8.x/</link><description>Recent content in 8.x on Gary Flynn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/8.x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for changing the IP address range used by the internal Kubernetes cluster, which is great news as many organisation already use the 10.244.0.0/21 address space. Unfortunately if your network already uses the ranges 10.244.0.0/22 or 10.244.4.0/22, you will likely encounter issues, such a provisioning timeouts.
To resolve this issue in vRA 8.2, run the below commands to view your current configuration, and to update to a new range.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Google Cloud Platform Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Google Cloud Platform (GCP) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For GCP, there is some preparation we need to do on the GCP Console, so head over to console.cloud.google.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Project you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Azure Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Microsoft Azure environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For Azure, there is some preparation we need to do on the Azure Portal, so head over to portal.azure.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Subscription you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup vSphere Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your vSphere environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For vSphere, enter the vCenter FQDN / IP address, the credentials to authenticate with and select a logical name. Under capabilities, enter &amp;quot;cloud:vsphere&amp;quot; as this will enable us to use tagging in the blueprint request forms.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</guid><description>
Today is a significant day for VMware with the announcements coming out primarily around vSphere 7 and the implementation of Project Tanzu. The vSphere client will now natively support running containers and VMs within the same unified console, the vSphere Client. One very interesting new feature is the VMware Lifecycle Manager (vLCM) that will be introduced to simplify the management of firmware, drivers and ESXi bundles. For more information on today's announcements, check out the blog here.</description></item></channel></rss>