<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>8.x on Gary Flynn</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/8.x/</link><description>Recent content in 8.x on Gary Flynn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/8.x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ - Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout-comments/</guid><description>
John Dias - Nov 3, 2021
Gary, this doesn't seem to impact embedded vRO - do you know a trick for that?
#### [Gary]( "garyflynnis@gmail.com") - Nov 4, 2021 G'day John. Unfortunately not. I mention this in the article, but for whatever reason, I can't see this change affecting vRO. I'm hoping it's a bug, but suspect it might be a 'feature'. All the best. Gary</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ – Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</guid><description>
By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session will timeout after 30 minutes of inactivity. For those looking to increase the session timeout value, this hasn't been possible before vRealize Automation 8.5. This all changes with the release of vRealize Automation 8.5, as documented in the release notes here.
To increase the session timeout from the default 30 minutes, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL.</description></item><item><title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform-comments/</guid><description>
vRA &amp;amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy – Gary Flynn - May 2, 2021
[…] Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform […]</description></item><item><title>vRA &amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy-comments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy-comments/</guid><description>
vExpert Cloud Management January 2021 Blog Digest - Möbius Business Technologies Ltd. - Feb 1, 2021
[…] vRA &amp;amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy by Gary Flynn (@GaryFlynnAU) Great Britain […]
#### [Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform &amp;#8211; Gary Flynn](https://garyflynn.com/technology/vmware/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/ "") - May 1, 2021 […] first two posts in this series cover the basics of Infrastructure as Code with vRA and Terraform along with creating your first Terraform configuration to deploy a vSphere virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>vRA &amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</guid><description>
On January 28th 2021, I presented at the Automation User Group about vRealize Automation and Terraform and how they work together to provide a new way to deploy your infrastructure. The recording of the session will be available here and the slides are available from here.
vRealize Automation Cloud What is Infrastructure as Code? Two Approaches: Imperative vs Declarative What is Terraform (OSS)? Additional Resources vRealize Automation Cloud VMware vRealize Automation (vRA) Cloud allows you to provide multi-cloud infrastructure and application delivery to your end-users.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range-comments/</guid><description>
Josh - May 3, 2021
We had attempted this in our environment unsuccessfully. After opening a case with vmware, we were informed that these steps are incorrect, and were provided the following procedure: • execute 'vracli upgrade exec -y --prepare --profile k8s-subnets' • take VM snapshot • change the subnets on the same node the upgrade command was started: 'vracli network k8s-subnets --cluster-cidr 10.224.0.0/22 --service-cidr 10.224.4.0/22' • execute upgrade with profile: 'vracli upgrade exec'</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for changing the IP address range used by the internal Kubernetes cluster, which is great news as many organisation already use the 10.244.0.0/21 address space. Unfortunately if your network already uses the ranges 10.244.0.0/22 or 10.244.4.0/22, you will likely encounter issues, such a provisioning timeouts.
To resolve this issue in vRA 8.2, run the below commands to view your current configuration, and to update to a new range.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account-comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account-comments/</guid><description>
yuki - Apr 4, 2021
Thank you very much. Cloud Zone is created. But after 10 min i got error like this :com.amazonaws.services.s3.model.AmazonS3Exception: Service Unavailable (Service: Amazon S3; Status Code: 503; Error Code: 503 Service Unavailable; Request ID: null; S3 Extended Request ID: null; Proxy: proxy-service.prelude.svc.cluster.local) java.util.concurrent.CompletionException: com.amazonaws.services.ec2.model.AmazonEC2Exception: null (Service: AmazonEC2; Status Code: 503; Error Code: 503 Service Unavailable; Request ID: null; Proxy: proxy-service.prelude.svc.cluster.local) Do you know somting about this?</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Amazon Web Services (AWS) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For AWS, we simply need to head over to the AWS Console console.aws.amazon.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the AWS account you want to integrate with.
To integrate vRA 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Google Cloud Platform Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Google Cloud Platform (GCP) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For GCP, there is some preparation we need to do on the GCP Console, so head over to console.cloud.google.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Project you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Azure Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Microsoft Azure environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For Azure, there is some preparation we need to do on the Azure Portal, so head over to portal.azure.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Subscription you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup vSphere Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your vSphere environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For vSphere, enter the vCenter FQDN / IP address, the credentials to authenticate with and select a logical name. Under capabilities, enter &amp;quot;cloud:vsphere&amp;quot; as this will enable us to use tagging in the blueprint request forms.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020-comments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020-comments/</guid><description>
vSphere 7.0 Link-O-Rama » Welcome to vSphere-land! - Mar 2, 2020
[…] vRealize Suite Announcement – March 2020 (Gary Flynn) vRealize Management 8.1 (vROPS, vRLI, vRA): What’s new (JohannStander) vRealize Operations Manager (vROps) 8.1 – A True Multi-Cloud Management Platform (VirtualG) vRealize Automation 8.1 – Network Automation (vRA4U) vRealize Automation 8.1 – General Enhancements (Part 1) (vRA4U) vRealize Automation 8.1 – General Enhancements (Part 2) (vRA4U) […]
#### [Анонс VMware vSphere 7 | vMind.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</guid><description>
Today is a significant day for VMware with the announcements coming out primarily around vSphere 7 and the implementation of Project Tanzu. The vSphere client will now natively support running containers and VMs within the same unified console, the vSphere Client. One very interesting new feature is the VMware Lifecycle Manager (vLCM) that will be introduced to simplify the management of firmware, drivers and ESXi bundles. For more information on today's announcements, check out the blog here.</description></item></channel></rss>