<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aria on Gary Flynn</title>
    <link>https://garyflynn.com/tags/aria/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aria on Gary Flynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.com/tags/aria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Aria Automation &amp; Terraform</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-one/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Using Terraform to consume Aria Automation / VCF Automation is easy to configure and to get started, have a read of the below code snippets. This guide will cover the initial setup and configuration of the Aria Automation Terraform provider and assumes that you have the Terraform executable installed locally. If not, install locally following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.hashicorp.com/terraform/install&#34;&gt;HashiCorp documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part One of this guide will cover authenticating to the Aria Automation / VCF Automation instance.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takeaways from VMware Explore EU 2022</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/takeaways-from-vmware-explore-eu-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/takeaways-from-vmware-explore-eu-2022/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;VMware Explore EU 2022 was personally my first ever large conference and what an event it was! The biggest benefit of attending for me was to finally meet so many people who are also part of the broader vCommunity, along with fellow vExperts and colleagues from vendors who I have been working very closely with over the past 2-3 years. To everyone I managed to say hello to, thank you for helping to make this a truly amazing event!&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Explore US 2022 Cloud Management Announcements</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vmware-explore-2022-cloud-management-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vmware-explore-2022-cloud-management-announcements/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;VMware Explore 2022 was set to be a big event for VMware, with the infamous VMworld branding being changed to VMware Explore along with this being the first in person event since 2019, due to COVID-19. Sure enough, there was no shortage of announcements and information available for everyone this year. Last year at VMworld 2021 we had the announcement of &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2021/10/introducing-project-ensemble.html&#34;&gt;Project Ensemble Tech Preview&lt;/a&gt; and this year we saw this formalise into VMware Aria Hub. In fact, the biggest announcement to come out of the event is the announcement of &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2022/08/introducing-vmware-aria.html&#34;&gt;VMware Aria&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
