<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homelab on Gary Flynn</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/homelab/</link><description>Recent content in Homelab on Gary Flynn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ - Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</guid><description>
By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session will timeout after 30 minutes of inactivity. For those looking to increase the session timeout value, this hasn't been possible before vRealize Automation 8.5. This all changes with the release of vRealize Automation 8.5, as documented in the release notes here.
To increase the session timeout from the default 30 minutes, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL.</description></item><item><title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</guid><description>
VMware has created a HashiCorp Terraform provider which can be used to set up your vRealize Automation (vRA) infrastructure, along with requesting deployments and consuming XaaS resources. This post will cover the basics of setting up vRA using Terraform.
The first two posts in this series cover the basics of Infrastructure as Code with vRA and Terraform along with creating your first Terraform configuration to deploy a vSphere virtual machine. To get started, have a read of the documentation available for either vRA 8 or vRA 7.</description></item><item><title>Create Your First vSphere Terraform Configuration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/create-your-first-vsphere-terraform-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 19:36:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/create-your-first-vsphere-terraform-configuration/</guid><description>
To get started with HashiCorp Terraform, you can download the simple executable file from HashiCorp here. To understand the basics of Infrastructure as Code and Terraform, have a read of the post available here.
Terraform configuration files are text files with a .tf file extension. To get started, create a new folder for this configuration, along with a file called vsphere.tf. The first part to creating a Terraform configuration file is to define the provider you will interact with.</description></item><item><title>vRA &amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</guid><description>
On January 28th 2021, I presented at the Automation User Group about vRealize Automation and Terraform and how they work together to provide a new way to deploy your infrastructure. The recording of the session will be available here and the slides are available from here.
vRealize Automation Cloud What is Infrastructure as Code? Two Approaches: Imperative vs Declarative What is Terraform (OSS)? Additional Resources vRealize Automation Cloud VMware vRealize Automation (vRA) Cloud allows you to provide multi-cloud infrastructure and application delivery to your end-users.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for changing the IP address range used by the internal Kubernetes cluster, which is great news as many organisation already use the 10.244.0.0/21 address space. Unfortunately if your network already uses the ranges 10.244.0.0/22 or 10.244.4.0/22, you will likely encounter issues, such a provisioning timeouts.
To resolve this issue in vRA 8.2, run the below commands to view your current configuration, and to update to a new range.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0 introduced a completely new architecture by running the vRA application itself on top of a Kubernetes (k8s) cluster. Unfortunately this was released with a hardcoded IP address range used by the internal k8s cluster. If your corporate network happened to be using the same IP addresses that were selected by the k8s cluster, then you would likely see plenty of errors in vRA.
Thankfully, vRealize Automation 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.2 - Terraform Configurations</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for running your Terraform (TF) configurations directly from the vRA interface. Simply register your code repository endpoint, either GitLab or GitHub, and select which Terraform configuration to run. The vRA logic will even map the deployed resources to your vRA Cloud Accounts, Cloud Zones, and deployed resource objects. This functionality is fantastic to extend the capabilities beyond the supported resource types. You could use the TF configurations to deploy an F5 load balancer, an Azure and AWS VM, as well as creating your Grafana dashboards and registering your Datadog agents all from a single configuration.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Amazon Web Services (AWS) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For AWS, we simply need to head over to the AWS Console console.aws.amazon.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the AWS account you want to integrate with.
To integrate vRA 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator - Kerberos Configuration File</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-orchestrator-kerberos-configuration-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 11:02:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-orchestrator-kerberos-configuration-file/</guid><description>
To configure Kerberos authentication with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO), the krb5.conf file must be set up for your specific environment and the domain you are connecting to. The location of the krb5.conf file is different for different versions and deployments of vRO, so the below list shows the locations of the krb5.conf file for vRO 7 vs vRO 8 and standalone deployments vs embedded with vRA deployments.
In vRO 7.x standalone, the krb5.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Google Cloud Platform Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Google Cloud Platform (GCP) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For GCP, there is some preparation we need to do on the GCP Console, so head over to console.cloud.google.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Project you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Azure Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Microsoft Azure environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For Azure, there is some preparation we need to do on the Azure Portal, so head over to portal.azure.com and authenticate with the account which has access to the Subscription you want to integrate with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup vSphere Cloud Account</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your vSphere environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For vSphere, enter the vCenter FQDN / IP address, the credentials to authenticate with and select a logical name. Under capabilities, enter &amp;quot;cloud:vsphere&amp;quot; as this will enable us to use tagging in the blueprint request forms.</description></item><item><title>Start the vRealize Orchestrator Configurator Service</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/start-the-vrealize-orchestrator-configurator-service/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 15:25:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/start-the-vrealize-orchestrator-configurator-service/</guid><description>
Once vRealize Automation 7.x is deployed, you must manually start the vRealize Orchestrator Configurator service to access the Configuration interface.
To do this, log into the vRealize Automation appliance by SSH using PuTTY (or your preferred Secure Shell client).
Run this command to verify that the service is set to automatically start.
1chkconfig vco-configurator If the service reports &amp;quot;off&amp;quot;, run this command to enable an automatic restart of the vRealize Orchestrator Configurator service when the vRealize Automation appliance is rebooted in future.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Services</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:47:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services/</guid><description>
In the previous post we configured vRA 8.0 with a vSphere endpoint and in this post we are going to cover the different Services which are available. vRA 8.0 has four main components or services, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Great, but what is the role of each service?
Cloud Assembly The Cloud Assembly service is the multi-cloud provisioning service and is where the bulk of your time will be spent.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Getting Started (Quickstart)</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:41:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</guid><description>
In the previous post we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRA and configure it for use. vRA 8.0 is a fundamental change from 7.x and it now consists of four main components, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Let's get vRA 8.0 configured! Load up the vRA homepage https:/// where you are greeted with the welcome page. One thing to note is that the new vRA 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Log Insight 8.x - Getting Started</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-log-insight-8x-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 10:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-log-insight-8x-getting-started/</guid><description>
In the previous post we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRLI and configure it for use. vRLI 8.0 has some significant improvements including Unlimited Exports of data (increased from 20,000 events), Content Pack Updates and a new OS in the form of Photon OS. For more information check out the VMware blog post here which includes details of how the single upgrade file will also move the OS from SUSE to Photon!</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite 2019 - Deploy using vRSLCM</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 09:13:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/</guid><description>
In the previous post we went over the vRSLCM configuration and now we are ready to deploy the vRealize Suite of products. Before we start, I can not stress this enough... Read the release notes!! There are countless changes to each of the products and vRA 8.0 especially is missing some features which may return in vRA 8.1 or later.
vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 - Release Notes vRealize Automation 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 Configuration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 21:02:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/</guid><description>
In the previous post we went over the vRSLCM Easy Installer which deployed vRSLCM 8.0 and vIDM 8.0. The installations went smoothly with no reported issues.
Let's log into the vRSLCM UI by navigating to https:/// and log in with the username &amp;quot;admin@local&amp;quot; and the password you set in the deployment in the previous steps. Note the default username has changed from previous versions and is no longer admin@localhost. Don't get caught out trying to log in with the wrong username!</description></item><item><title>vRealize Suite 2019 - Easy Installer</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/</guid><description>
VMware has just announced the latest release of the vRealize Suite (2019) and with it comes vRealize Automation 8.0 (vRA), vRealize Log Insight 8.0 (vRLI), vRealize Operations Manager 8.0 (vROps) and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 (vRSLCM). Noticeably absent is vRealize Business for Cloud (vRBC), as this product has been deprecated and the functionality has been migrated to vROps.
Announcing General Availability of vRealize Suite 2019, vCloud Suite 2019, and vCloud Suite 2019 Platinum!</description></item><item><title>Homelab Setup Part 3 - vCenter Install &amp; Configure</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/homelab-setup-part-3-vcenter-install-configure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 10:41:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/homelab-setup-part-3-vcenter-install-configure/</guid><description>
To setup the NUC and install ESXi, follow part one of this guide. To configure the basic vSAN configuration for deployments pre vCenter 6.7, follow part two of this guide.
vCenter Appliance Installation With the Intel NUCs set up (and a vSAN datastore created if running pre 6.7 vCenter), it is time to install the vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA). As you probably know, the Windows vCenter Server is deprecated, so the vCSA will be deployed.</description></item><item><title>ESXi Install and Configure</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/esxi-install-and-configure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 09:25:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/esxi-install-and-configure/</guid><description>
This guide will cover the ESXi installation and configuration process. If installing ESXi onto a bare-metal server from a USB, follow my guide here on how to create a bootable USB installer. Once you have your installation media ready, either a USB installer or the downloaded ISO, insert / attach the media and power on your server. If you are doing this in a nested ESXi environment, attach the media via the VMware Remote Console.</description></item><item><title>Homelab Setup Part 2 - vSAN Configuration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/homelab-setup-part-2-vsan-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 10:36:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/homelab-setup-part-2-vsan-configuration/</guid><description>
To setup the NUC and install ESXi, follow part one of this guide. The following is the process to bootstrap loading the vCenter Server Appliance onto a vSAN datastore. This process was replaced in vCenter 6.7 which provides this capability natively through the installer. If you are deploying vCenter 6.7+, skip through to part three.
vSAN Configuration To install vCenter you need the datastore in place, which for my environment is vSAN.</description></item><item><title>Homelab Setup Part 1 - Intel NUC</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/homelab-setup-part-1-intel-nuc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 16:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/homelab-setup-part-1-intel-nuc/</guid><description>
I have recently decided to purchase a homelab for myself to assist with getting my certifications up to date and after much research and procrastinating I have gone with the setup below. Overall I have been very happy with the performance and compatibility of everything and I have tried to link to all of the useful blogs that helped me along the way.
Hardware 1 x TP-Link TL-SG108E 8 Port Switch (Amazon UK)</description></item></channel></rss>