<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VRA on Gary Flynn</title>
    <link>https://garyflynn.com/tags/vra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VRA on Gary Flynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.com/tags/vra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-change-internal-kubernetes-ip-range/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for changing the IP address range used by the internal Kubernetes cluster, which is great news as many organisation already use the 10.244.0.0/21 address space. Unfortunately if your network already uses the ranges 10.244.0.0/22 or 10.244.4.0/22, you will likely encounter issues, such a provisioning timeouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue in vRA 8.2, run the below commands to view your current configuration, and to update to a new range.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.5&#43; - Increase Session Timeout</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session will timeout after 30 minutes of inactivity. For those looking to increase the session timeout value, this hasn&#39;t been possible before vRealize Automation 8.5. This all changes with the release of vRealize Automation 8.5, as documented in the release notes &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-vRealize-Automation/8.5/rn/vmware-vrealize-automation-85-release-notes.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the session timeout from the default 30 minutes, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL. Another option would be to run the same API calls in Postman.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;VMware has created a HashiCorp Terraform provider which can be used to set up your vRealize Automation (vRA) infrastructure, along with requesting deployments and consuming XaaS resources. This post will cover the basics of setting up vRA using Terraform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two posts in this series cover the basics of &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/&#34;&gt;Infrastructure as Code with vRA and Terraform&lt;/a&gt; along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/create-your-first-vsphere-terraform-configuration/&#34;&gt;creating your first Terraform configuration to deploy a vSphere virtual machine&lt;/a&gt;. To get started, have a read of the documentation available for either &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.terraform.io/providers/vmware/vra/latest/docs&#34;&gt;vRA 8&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.terraform.io/providers/vmware/vra7/latest/docs&#34;&gt;vRA 7&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Hide Quickstart UI</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-hide-quickstart-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-hide-quickstart-ui/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session log you into the Services page, when you and your users are greeted with the Quickstart banner. The easiest way to remove this is to configure a vSphere Cloud Account, however for some environments, vSphere isn&#39;t an endpoint used. In this case, to remove the banner, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL. Another option would be to run the same API calls in Postman.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRA &amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;On January 28th 2021, I presented at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autoug.io/&#34;&gt;Automation User Group&lt;/a&gt; about vRealize Automation and Terraform and how they work together to provide a new way to deploy your infrastructure. The recording of the session will be available &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Q1XcuxTL6CQ&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the slides are available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vRA-and-Terraform-A-New-Way-to-Deploy.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/#vrealize-automation-cloud&#34;&gt;vRealize Automation Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/#what-is-infrastructure-as-code&#34;&gt;What is Infrastructure as Code?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/#two-approaches-imperative-vs-declarative&#34;&gt;Two Approaches: Imperative vs Declarative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/#what-is-terraform-oss&#34;&gt;What is Terraform (OSS)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/#additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vrealize-automation-cloud&#34;&gt;vRealize Automation Cloud&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware vRealize Automation (vRA) Cloud allows you to provide multi-cloud infrastructure and application delivery to your end-users. It enhances the visibility of your machines across your different private and public cloud providers, enables collaboration and provides continuous delivery and release automation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0 introduced a completely new architecture by running the vRA application itself on top of a Kubernetes (k8s) cluster. Unfortunately this was released with a hardcoded IP address range used by the internal k8s cluster. If your corporate network happened to be using the same IP addresses that were selected by the k8s cluster, then you would likely see plenty of errors in vRA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, vRealize Automation 8.2 added support for changing the internal IP address range used by the Kubernetes cluster. Unfortunately, there is a bug in the code where only the 10.0.0.0/8 and 127.0.0.0/8 address spaces are supported. If you choose to use the 192.168.0.0/16 address space, the vRA deployment won&#39;t start-up. When running the command &amp;quot;kubectl get pods -n prelude&amp;quot;, the &amp;quot;catalog-service-app&amp;quot; pod will show as 0/1 Ready, and Running.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.2 - Terraform Configurations</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for running your Terraform (TF) configurations directly from the vRA interface. Simply register your code repository endpoint, either GitLab or GitHub, and select which Terraform configuration to run. The vRA logic will even map the deployed resources to your vRA Cloud Accounts, Cloud Zones, and deployed resource objects. This functionality is fantastic to extend the capabilities beyond the supported resource types. You could use the TF configurations to deploy an F5 load balancer, an Azure and AWS VM, as well as creating your Grafana dashboards and registering your Datadog agents all from a single configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Amazon Web Services (AWS) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For AWS, we simply need to head over to the AWS Console &lt;a href=&#34;https://console.aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;console.aws.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; and authenticate with the account which has access to the AWS account you want to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To integrate vRA 8.x with AWS, there are 2 configuration IDs and some permissions that need to be set up which we need to complete and provide to the vRA portal. These are covered in the sections listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup GitHub Integration</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.x provides native integration to GitHub.com to share and sync your Blueprints and Action Based Extensibility (ABX) scripts. This integration is provided as a way to edit your blueprints and ABX scripts as Infrastructure as Code (IaC) objects and for vRA to then consume the changes once they are updated and committed to your repository. This integration is not designed as a way to backup or export your content to GitHub. Integration in vRA 8.0 / vRA 8.0.1 is only available to GitHub.com and not GitHub Enterprise Cloud or GitHub Enterprise Self-Hosted.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Google Cloud Platform Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Google Cloud Platform (GCP) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For GCP, there is some preparation we need to do on the GCP Console, so head over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://console.cloud.google.com&#34;&gt;console.cloud.google.com&lt;/a&gt; and authenticate with the account which has access to the Project you want to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Azure Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Microsoft Azure environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For Azure, there is some preparation we need to do on the Azure Portal, so head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.azure.com&#34;&gt;portal.azure.com&lt;/a&gt; and authenticate with the account which has access to the Subscription you want to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup vSphere Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your vSphere environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For vSphere, enter the vCenter FQDN / IP address, the credentials to authenticate with and select a logical name. Under capabilities, enter &amp;quot;cloud:vsphere&amp;quot; as this will enable us to use tagging in the blueprint request forms. Validate the credentials and once they are validated, select which datacenters to allow provisioning to, followed by selecting Add.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite Announcement - March 2020</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-announcement-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today is a significant day for VMware with the announcements coming out primarily around vSphere 7 and the implementation of Project Tanzu. The vSphere client will now natively support running containers and VMs within the same unified console, the vSphere Client. One very interesting new feature is the VMware Lifecycle Manager (vLCM) that will be introduced to simplify the management of firmware, drivers and ESXi bundles. For more information on today&#39;s announcements, check out the blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2020/03/vsphere-7.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. But what about the vRealize Suite announcements? That&#39;s what we are really interested in!&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRA 7.x vs vRA 8.x - Which Version to Deploy?</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/which-version-of-vra-to-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 16:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/which-version-of-vra-to-deploy/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;VMware has recently released vRealize Automation 8.0 and with this comes a complete redesign of the vRealize Automation product. Are you just starting out on your Cloud Management Platform (CMP) journey and not quite sure which version to deploy? Hopefully this blog will help you understand some of the key differences between vRA 7.x and vRA 8.x and some familiar features which are missing from vRA 8.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first place to start is by reading this excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://communities.vmware.com/people/daphnissov/blog/2019/10/18/vrealize-automation-vra-8-faq&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Chip Zoller (daphnissov) on the VMware Community Forums. This vRA 8 FAQ provides plenty of answers to some of the obvious questions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;With the introduction of vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0, the traditional appliance VAMI page is gone. This is replaced with the vRA CLI and the kubernetes command line tools. This post will show some of the more common CLI commands you may need. To use all of the commands below, use SSH to connect to the appliance and log in with the root username and password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#check-pods--services-status&#34;&gt;Check Pods / &#39;Services&#39; Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#display-vra-cluster-status&#34;&gt;Display vRA Cluster Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#verify-the-vra-deployment-status&#34;&gt;Verify the vRA Deployment Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#check-deployment-log-file&#34;&gt;Check Deployment Log File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#generate-a-log-bundle&#34;&gt;Generate a Log Bundle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#stopping--shut-down-vra-cluster&#34;&gt;Stopping / Shut down vRA Cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#starting-vra-cluster&#34;&gt;Starting vRA Cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#vra-8x-error---bad-gateway&#34;&gt;vRA 8.x Error - Bad Gateway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#vra-just-not-working&#34;&gt;vRA just not working...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#remove-vm-from-inventory-without-deleting-the-vm&#34;&gt;Remove VM from Inventory without deleting the VM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-troubleshooting/#remove-vra-integration-with-vrealize-log-insight&#34;&gt;Remove vRA integration with vRealize Log Insight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-pods--services-status&#34;&gt;Check Pods / &#39;Services&#39; Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the traditional vRA services are replaced with kubernetes containers, you can still check the running status of them using the command below. This command will show the running status, the age and the number of restarts for each pod or &#39;service&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Services</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-services/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we configured vRA 8.0 with a vSphere endpoint and in this post we are going to cover the different Services which are available. vRA 8.0 has four main components or services, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Great, but what is the role of each service?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/images/vra8-services.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-assembly&#34;&gt;Cloud Assembly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cloud Assembly service is the multi-cloud provisioning service and is where the bulk of your time will be spent. The Cloud Assembly service is where you can create your SDDC private cloud and it is also an abstraction layer across multiple clouds. This abstraction allows you to create blueprints which can be used to deploy applications across different cloud providers, mapping the cloud constructs of one public cloud provider with another. All of the usual features are there including viewing your existing deployments, creating blueprints and configuring Infrastructure. The addition of the &amp;quot;Guided Setup&amp;quot; on the right hand side helps with understanding how all of the terminology fits everything together. The Infrastructure tab in Cloud Assembly is where most of the configuration is done. Here you can create the different projects, cloud zones, flavour and image mappings and network and storage profiles. The infrastructure tab is also where the cloud accounts are defined and the compute, network, security, storage etc are all deployed, along with the Kubernetes integration. The table below maps the vRA 7.x constructs to the vRA 8.x constructs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Getting Started (Quickstart)</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRA and configure it for use. vRA 8.0 is a fundamental change from 7.x and it now consists of four main components, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Let&#39;s get vRA 8.0 configured! Load up the vRA homepage https://&amp;lt;vRA FDQN&amp;gt;/ where you are greeted with the welcome page. One thing to note is that the new vRA 8.0 appliance does not contain a VAMI, instead non-UI configuration is done using the &amp;quot;vracli&amp;quot; commands on the appliance shell.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite 2019 - Deploy using vRSLCM</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 09:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we went over the vRSLCM configuration and now we are ready to deploy the vRealize Suite of products. Before we start, I can not stress this enough... Read the release notes!! There are countless changes to each of the products and vRA 8.0 especially is missing some features which may return in vRA 8.1 or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-vRealize-Suite-Lifecycle-Manager/2019/rn/VMware-vRealize-Suite-Lifecycle-Manager-80-Release-Notes.html&#34;&gt;vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 - Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Automation/8.0/rn/vRealize-Automation-80-release-notes.html&#34;&gt;vRealize Automation 8.0 - Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Log-Insight/8.0/rn/vRealize-Log-Insight-80.html&#34;&gt;vRealize Log Insight 8.0 - Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Operations-Manager/8.0/rn/vRealize-Operations-Manager-80.html&#34;&gt;vRealize Operations Manager 8.0 - Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Orchestrator/8.0/rn/VMware-vRealize-Orchestrator-80-Release-Notes.html&#34;&gt;vRealize Orchestrator 8.0 - Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vrealize-suite-2019-deployment&#34;&gt;vRealize Suite 2019 Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this environment is just your homelab, you can leverage the default datacenter otherwise it is best to create a new datacenter. To create a Datacenter, log into vRSLCM and select Lifecycle Operations &amp;gt; Datacenters on the left, then Add Datacenter. Enter a name along with the location and click Save. Add a vCenter Server to your new datacenter and Save. You should now see two datacenters. One called &amp;quot;default_datacenter&amp;quot; located in Palo Alto, California, US which contains the vIDM installation, and another new one for your new deployment. In vRSLCM 8.0.1 you can now edit the location of the default datacenter to match your actual location.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 Configuration</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 21:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-lifecycle-manager-8-0-configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we went over the vRSLCM Easy Installer which deployed vRSLCM 8.0 and vIDM 8.0. The installations went smoothly with no reported issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s log into the vRSLCM UI by navigating to https://&amp;lt;vRSLCM FQDN or IP&amp;gt;/ and log in with the username &amp;quot;admin@local&amp;quot; and the password you set in the deployment in the previous steps. Note the default username has changed from previous versions and is no longer admin@localhost. Don&#39;t get caught out trying to log in with the wrong username!&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Suite 2019 - Easy Installer</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-easy-installer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;VMware has just announced the latest release of the vRealize Suite (2019) and with it comes vRealize Automation 8.0 (vRA), vRealize Log Insight 8.0 (vRLI), vRealize Operations Manager 8.0 (vROps) and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 (vRSLCM). Noticeably absent is vRealize Business for Cloud (vRBC), as this product has been deprecated and the functionality has been migrated to vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/10/vrealize-suite-2019-vcloud-suite-2019-ga.html&#34;&gt;Announcing General Availability of vRealize Suite 2019, vCloud Suite 2019, and vCloud Suite 2019 Platinum!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/08/vrslcm-8-0-whats-new.html&#34;&gt;vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager 8.0 – What’s New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/10/announcing-general-availability-of-vmware-vrealize-automation-8-0.html&#34;&gt;Announcing General Availability of VMware vRealize Automation 8.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/10/whats-new-in-vrealize-log-insight-8-0.html&#34;&gt;What’s new in vRealize Log Insight 8.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/10/whats-new-in-vrealize-operations-8-0-2.html&#34;&gt;What’s New in vRealize Operations 8.0?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vxpresss.blogspot.com/2019/10/everything-you-need-to-know-about.html&#34;&gt;Everything you need to know about the vRealize Operations 8.0 release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the exciting announcements out of the way, let&#39;s get these installed!&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRA 7.x Reclamation Machine Usage Thresholds</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-7-x-reclamation-machine-usage-thresholds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vra-7-x-reclamation-machine-usage-thresholds/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In vRealize Automation 7.x, you can discover Deployments for reclamation in the &lt;strong&gt;Administration &amp;gt; Reclamation &amp;gt; Deployments&lt;/strong&gt; (Tenant Administrator) view or the &lt;strong&gt;Administration &amp;gt; Reclamation &amp;gt; Tenant Machines&lt;/strong&gt; (IaaS Administrator) view. The Advanced Search feature can be selected clicking &lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the top right corner and you can search for VMs with Low or High CPU usage along with several other options. But what are the actual thresholds that vRA uses when you select &amp;quot;Low CPU&amp;quot;? The table below describes exactly what each of the metrics are, for each advanced search option.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downgrade / Remove vRA License</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/downgrade-remove-vra-license/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/downgrade-remove-vra-license/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I recently had the requirement to remove an existing vRealize Suite Enterprise key from vRealize Automation 7.3.1 and replace it with a vRealize Suite Advanced key. When you try to replace the license key from the VAMI, you will receive an error stating that you cannot downgrade license keys &amp;quot;Unable to downgrade existing license edition&amp;quot;. To replace the license you must do the following. Note, this is 100% &lt;strong&gt;not supported&lt;/strong&gt; by VMware so use it at your own risk and always do it first in a test environment, and always ensure you have backups.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
