<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Gary Flynn</title>
    <link>https://garyflynn.com/tags/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Gary Flynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 21:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.com/tags/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aria Automation &amp; Terraform - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 21:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-two/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This guide will cover the creation of the Aria Automation Cloud Accounts and Cloud Zones. Before getting started, follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-one/&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; to configure the Aria Automation / VCF Automation provider for terraform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first terraform resource to create is the Cloud Accounts. Create a new file called &amp;quot;cloud_accounts.tf&amp;quot; and add the code below. The first account to be added is to a vSphere environment. The resource is of type &#39;vra_cloud_account_vsphere&#39; and called &#39;homelab&#39; in this example. A second data source is required to enumerate the available regions within the vSphere environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Aria Automation &amp; Terraform</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/aria-automation-and-terraform-part-one/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Using Terraform to consume Aria Automation / VCF Automation is easy to configure and to get started, have a read of the below code snippets. This guide will cover the initial setup and configuration of the Aria Automation Terraform provider and assumes that you have the Terraform executable installed locally. If not, install locally following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.hashicorp.com/terraform/install&#34;&gt;HashiCorp documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part One of this guide will cover authenticating to the Aria Automation / VCF Automation instance.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Amazon Web Services Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-aws-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Amazon Web Services (AWS) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For AWS, we simply need to head over to the AWS Console &lt;a href=&#34;https://console.aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;console.aws.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; and authenticate with the account which has access to the AWS account you want to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To integrate vRA 8.x with AWS, there are 2 configuration IDs and some permissions that need to be set up which we need to complete and provide to the vRA portal. These are covered in the sections listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Google Cloud Platform Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-gcp-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Google Cloud Platform (GCP) environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For GCP, there is some preparation we need to do on the GCP Console, so head over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://console.cloud.google.com&#34;&gt;console.cloud.google.com&lt;/a&gt; and authenticate with the account which has access to the Project you want to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup Azure Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-azure-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your Microsoft Azure environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For Azure, there is some preparation we need to do on the Azure Portal, so head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.azure.com&#34;&gt;portal.azure.com&lt;/a&gt; and authenticate with the account which has access to the Subscription you want to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup vSphere Cloud Account</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-vsphere-cloud-account/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;vRealize Automation 8.x can integrate with several cloud providers, and to do this for your vSphere environment, select Cloud Assembly &amp;gt; Infrastructure &amp;gt; Connections &amp;gt; Cloud Accounts and create each of the cloud integrations you require. For vSphere, enter the vCenter FQDN / IP address, the credentials to authenticate with and select a logical name. Under capabilities, enter &amp;quot;cloud:vsphere&amp;quot; as this will enable us to use tagging in the blueprint request forms. Validate the credentials and once they are validated, select which datacenters to allow provisioning to, followed by selecting Add.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Getting Started (Quickstart)</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-automation-8x-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRA and configure it for use. vRA 8.0 is a fundamental change from 7.x and it now consists of four main components, Cloud Assembly, Service Broker, Code Stream and Orchestrator. Let&#39;s get vRA 8.0 configured! Load up the vRA homepage https://&amp;lt;vRA FDQN&amp;gt;/ where you are greeted with the welcome page. One thing to note is that the new vRA 8.0 appliance does not contain a VAMI, instead non-UI configuration is done using the &amp;quot;vracli&amp;quot; commands on the appliance shell.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Log Insight 8.x - Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-log-insight-8x-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 10:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-log-insight-8x-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://garyflynn.com/post/vrealize-suite-2019-deploy-using-vrslcm/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we deployed all of the vRealize Suite products and we are now ready to log into vRLI and configure it for use. vRLI 8.0 has some significant improvements including Unlimited Exports of data (increased from 20,000 events), Content Pack Updates and a new OS in the form of Photon OS. For more information check out the VMware blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/management/2019/10/whats-new-in-vrealize-log-insight-8-0.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; which includes details of how the single upgrade file will also move the OS from SUSE to Photon! Very impressive!&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
