<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vRA 8 on Gary Flynn</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/vra-8/</link><description>Recent content in vRA 8 on Gary Flynn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyflynn.github.io/tags/vra-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ - Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout-comments/</guid><description>
John Dias - Nov 3, 2021
Gary, this doesn't seem to impact embedded vRO - do you know a trick for that?
#### [Gary]( "garyflynnis@gmail.com") - Nov 4, 2021 G'day John. Unfortunately not. I mention this in the article, but for whatever reason, I can't see this change affecting vRO. I'm hoping it's a bug, but suspect it might be a 'feature'. All the best. Gary</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.5+ – Increase Session Timeout</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-85-increase-session-timeout/</guid><description>
By default, a vRealize Automation 8.x session will timeout after 30 minutes of inactivity. For those looking to increase the session timeout value, this hasn't been possible before vRealize Automation 8.5. This all changes with the release of vRealize Automation 8.5, as documented in the release notes here.
To increase the session timeout from the default 30 minutes, a simple API call is all that is required. The below code can be run from either the appliance directly, or from your desktop PC using cURL.</description></item><item><title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform-comments/</guid><description>
vRA &amp;amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy – Gary Flynn - May 2, 2021
[…] Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform […]</description></item><item><title>Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/</guid><description>
VMware has created a HashiCorp Terraform provider which can be used to set up your vRealize Automation (vRA) infrastructure, along with requesting deployments and consuming XaaS resources. This post will cover the basics of setting up vRA using Terraform.
The first two posts in this series cover the basics of Infrastructure as Code with vRA and Terraform along with creating your first Terraform configuration to deploy a vSphere virtual machine. To get started, have a read of the documentation available for either vRA 8 or vRA 7.</description></item><item><title>vRA &amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy-comments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy-comments/</guid><description>
vExpert Cloud Management January 2021 Blog Digest - Möbius Business Technologies Ltd. - Feb 1, 2021
[…] vRA &amp;amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy by Gary Flynn (@GaryFlynnAU) Great Britain […]
#### [Setup vRealize Automation using Terraform &amp;#8211; Gary Flynn](https://garyflynn.com/technology/vmware/setup-vrealize-automation-using-terraform/ "") - May 1, 2021 […] first two posts in this series cover the basics of Infrastructure as Code with vRA and Terraform along with creating your first Terraform configuration to deploy a vSphere virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>vRA &amp; Terraform: A New Way to Deploy</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 10:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vra-and-terraform-a-new-way-to-deploy/</guid><description>
On January 28th 2021, I presented at the Automation User Group about vRealize Automation and Terraform and how they work together to provide a new way to deploy your infrastructure. The recording of the session will be available here and the slides are available from here.
vRealize Automation Cloud What is Infrastructure as Code? Two Approaches: Imperative vs Declarative What is Terraform (OSS)? Additional Resources vRealize Automation Cloud VMware vRealize Automation (vRA) Cloud allows you to provide multi-cloud infrastructure and application delivery to your end-users.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed-comments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed-comments/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation 8.x – Change Internal Kubernetes IP Range – Gary Flynn - Dec 4, 2020
[…] when the Kubernetes internal IP address space is changed to use the 192.168.0.0/16 address space. This post resolves the issue, while VMware develop a patch to resolve the […]</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - vRA Not Starting if K8s IP Range is Changed</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-vra-not-starting-if-k8s-ip-range-is-changed/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.0 introduced a completely new architecture by running the vRA application itself on top of a Kubernetes (k8s) cluster. Unfortunately this was released with a hardcoded IP address range used by the internal k8s cluster. If your corporate network happened to be using the same IP addresses that were selected by the k8s cluster, then you would likely see plenty of errors in vRA.
Thankfully, vRealize Automation 8.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.2 - Terraform Configurations</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations-comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations-comments/</guid><description>
Using vRA 8.2 Terraform cloud templates to deploy AWS resources - TG-TEST100 - Jan 4, 2021
[…] vRealize Automation 8.2 – Terraform Configurations […]</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.2 - Terraform Configurations</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-82-terraform-configurations/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.2 added support for running your Terraform (TF) configurations directly from the vRA interface. Simply register your code repository endpoint, either GitLab or GitHub, and select which Terraform configuration to run. The vRA logic will even map the deployed resources to your vRA Cloud Accounts, Cloud Zones, and deployed resource objects. This functionality is fantastic to extend the capabilities beyond the supported resource types. You could use the TF configurations to deploy an F5 load balancer, an Azure and AWS VM, as well as creating your Grafana dashboards and registering your Datadog agents all from a single configuration.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup GitHub Integration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration-comments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration-comments/</guid><description>
Nithin - Jul 4, 2021
Getting time out error and 404 error when synced with github for cloud templates and abx actions. How to resolve the issue ?</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 8.x - Setup GitHub Integration</title><link>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyflynn.github.io/post/vrealize-automation-8x-setup-github-integration/</guid><description>
vRealize Automation (vRA) 8.x provides native integration to GitHub.com to share and sync your Blueprints and Action Based Extensibility (ABX) scripts. This integration is provided as a way to edit your blueprints and ABX scripts as Infrastructure as Code (IaC) objects and for vRA to then consume the changes once they are updated and committed to your repository. This integration is not designed as a way to backup or export your content to GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>